friend.
That's what I think ABOUT COMFY UI.
SPAGHETTI!
TAKE MY MONEY, GANG.
I'M DONE WITH COMFY, on God. So, today
we are going to be running and testing
Minimax H3, the new top-of-the-line
video model that is available for local
use through Simply Gen. If you guys
don't know what Simply Gen is, before I
go any further, I have a video where I
showcase all the features that Simply
Gen offers. But, in a nutshell, what
basically is Comfy UI packaged into a
super intuitive and easy-to-use UI, and
it basically takes all of the stress and
headache that Comfy UI usually comes
with and relieves that for us. So, if
you want to check it out, I highly
recommend it. The link to Simply Gen is
in the description, and if you want to
check out the first video that I made
about Simply Gen, where I kind of go
through an exhaustive overview of all
that they offer, the link to that video
is in the description as well. So, if
you're not up-to-date on what Minimax H3
is, Minimax H3 is a brand new video
generation model that you can use
locally on your device, and it generates
video and audio together in a single
pass. So, dialogue, effects, and music
already match the action instead of
getting dubbed on afterwards. That's
pretty much the headline feature, but
the video quality is also really good,
and the prompt adherence is great as
well. And that's pretty much the main
reason that it feels different from most
local video models. So, the first thing
that we're going to need to do is head
over to the marketplace tab towards the
bottom of the left-hand menu, and there
you should see Minimax H3. It should be
one of the top options there. If it's
not, you can just head over to the video
tab and search for it. And you're going
to click choose variant, and once you go
to select the variant, you'll see that
there's only one option for the size of
the model. It's the pruned in-date
version of the model, and it says that
it needs around 16 GB of VRAM. One of
the owners and developers of Simply Gen
has told me that people have been able
to get this to run on as low as 8 GB of
VRAM, but you're probably going to be
looking at needing somewhere around 32
GB of system RAM in order to run this,
no matter what size GPU you have. But,
if you have 16 GB of VRAM and 32 GB of
RAM, this will run no problem on your
system. I'm running this on my brand new
computer that I just built that has a
5090. So, I'm going to go ahead and
install the pruned Inpaint version. And
all this does is just install a
template. The model is yet to be
downloaded, and I'll show you how we're
going to do that right now. So, since
I'm on my brand new device, I don't have
Simply Gen configured, and I don't have
any presets or anything installed. So,
I'm going to go ahead and after
installing that preset, I'm going to go
over to the Generate tab on the
left-hand side and click video. And then
you'll see once you install the preset
that you have MiniMax H3, the local
variant here. And if we open up that
menu, we'll see that we have a few
different options here. We have text to
video, image to video, and reference to
video. Now, you'll see on each of these
models that it says local needs around
40 GB of disk space to install. So, make
sure that you have enough space on your
SSD to install these models. Today,
we're going to be using image to video,
but if you're lacking a good source of
reference photos or just don't feel like
looking for some, you can always use the
text to video model. So, I'm going to
click at Generate Now on the image to
video template. And once we select
Generate Now on the template that you're
desiring to use, we will see that it
asks us for reference images, prompting,
the shot type, dialogue, lighting, and
so on. And we're going to configure all
of that soon, but the first thing that
we need to do before anything else is
obviously install this preset locally.
So, I'm going to go ahead and click
Install Preset Locally here. Anywhere
from 480 pixels all the way up to 768
pixels requires around 12 GB of VRAM. If
you go up to 928, that requires 16 GB or
more of VRAM. And finally, if we want to
generate in the maximum quality allowed,
we're going to need over 24 GB of VRAM.
So, depending on the size of your
graphics card, this is going to
determine what size videos you're
actually able to generate. Now, I'd also
like to point out that the timing and
duration also is pretty VRAM intensive.
We can see here that longer duration
videos require more VRAM. All right, so
just a short few moments later, we have
installed all of the models required to
run MiniMax H3 within Simply Gen. So,
before we go any further, this is the
part I actually want to focus on. Prompt
detail is what separates a mediocre
generation from a great one. On the
official ComfyUI website, there's
actually a prompting guide on how to
write good prompts to get good output
from Minimax H3. I will flash that on
screen quickly. And if you actually read
the prompt writing guide section on
screen now, you'll see that Minimax
publishes an official video prompt
writing guide for the base generation
modes. So, you have text to video, image
to video, first and last frame to video,
and so on. The guide explains how to
structure a prompt into time shots with
camera movements and audios, and
includes examples for each mode. So, in
the description of this video, I will
link the video prompt writing guide that
Minimax has published officially on
their Hugging Face repo. To get the full
scope of how to prompt Minimax and get
good output, that you guys head over
there and actually read the entire
repository for yourself. It'll help you
a ton. So, with that being said, to
actually know how to guide your prompt,
you're going to obviously need a
reference photo. So, I took a quick
detour through Simply Gen and generated
this reference photo with Crate 2 via
the template that they provide in the
marketplace. And then I went ahead and
used the Seed VR 2 upscaler that is also
available within Simply Gen and upscaled
this photo, so that way our reference
photo provides plenty of detail to get
the best quality out of Minimax H3. On
screen quickly is the reference photo
that we're using.
And so now I'm going to use the
prompting guide that has been provided
by the official creators of Minimax H3
to guide this generation. So, we have
provided a nice detailed prompt that
will guide our generation using the
rules that Minimax has provided for us.
If we scroll down, we can select things
like the shot type and angle. For this
particular instance, I'm using a wide
shot 16 by 9 resolution photo, so I am
going to select wide shot. You can
specify things such as environment,
lighting source, atmosphere, and so on.
And again, here in the aspect ratio, we
just want to make sure that we have the
proper aspect ratio selected. So, if
you're using a 16 by 9 photo, make sure
that you match that aspect ratio
roughly. I'm going to use the 768 pixel
native resolution. Like I said, we're
currently running 32 GB of VRAM, so this
should be absolutely no problem for us.
And for the duration, I am going to go
up to 7 seconds. Now, if you expand the
more advanced options, you can see
things like the camera movement. If you
want a static shot, which would
replicate something like a camera fixed
on a tripod, that's where you can
specify that. Or if you want like a
handheld iPhone style video, as if
somebody else was recording it, you can
also specify that. I wouldn't recommend
changing the steps. There's also a
negative prompt field where you can
specify anything that you're not wanting
in your generations. So, with all these
settings selected, I am going to
generate. Now, while my generation
processes, although I'm using the local
model that I installed to my device, if
you are actually limited by your VRAM
and can't use Minimax H3 on your local
device, a solution native to their
platform. You can generate videos using
their cloud service. While this is a
credit-based system, this still means
that you can use Simply Gen with any
system configuration that you may be
working with. Over on the side panel
here, we can see where our generation is
currently at in the step iteration
process. And I'll show you guys the
results as soon as that's finished. And
again, if you're wanting to learn how to
use Simply Gen to just generate basic
photos like the one that I've generated
for this video, I definitely recommend
checking out the first video that I made
on Simply Gen. Again, the link is in the
description of that. I go over pretty
much all the different ways and how you
can generate images using Simply Gen.
All right. So, now after getting that
output from our image to video runs, we
are going to modify the prompt so that
it works with text to video.
Something I just realized is that if you
download of image to video model, that
also includes the text to video model
within that download. So, no need to
download two different models for that.
It's just 40 GB for both of them.
All right, so after getting the results
with the soccer player, or football for
you Europeans, we're going to try
something that has dialogue. So, what
I'm going to do is make sure that I add
the character dialogue into the dialogue
box. Make sure that it's ticked on and
rate the dialogue in there.
>> friend
That's what I think about Comfy UI.
friend
>> All right.
That was amazing.
All right, so it seems that the prompt
adherence is much more flexible with
text to video. So, we're going to do a
few more generations with text to video.
I'm really liking the output that we're
getting. All right, so our third run
through with the text to video has just
finished. Let's check this out.
>> [snorts]
>> I think I'm going to try out Simply Gen.
Comfy UI is costing me tons of money on
new windows and monitors.
I think I'm going to try out Simply Gen.
Comfy UI is costing me tons of money on
new windows and monitors.
>> Hell yeah, bro. Okay, let's try out
Simply Gen.
>> [snorts]
>> All right, these are honestly hilarious.
I love these. I'm going to do one more.
The quality is so good, too. I can't
believe that I'm generating at 544 and
we're getting quality that looks like
that. All right, so we've generated the
final video demo that we're going to do
for this MiniMax H3 demo. Let's check it
out.
>> Simply Gen has saved me millions of
dollars in window and monitor repairs.
Now I'm rich, Simply Gen has
saved me millions of dollars in window
and monitor repairs. Now I'm rich,
>> Nice.
All right, so there's your little
three-part story on how you can save
money on window and monitor repairs if
you use Simply Gen instead of using
Comfy UI for the new MiniMax H3 video
generation model. If you guys enjoyed
the video, please make sure to like and
subscribe. Again, you can get Simply Gen
using the link in the description below,
and you can also find the resources that
I used for the prompting guidance, and
so on in the description as well. I hope
you guys enjoyed it, and I hope you guys
check out Simply Gen, and check out
Minimax H3.
Peace.